Not even a clue.
Have you been able to
come up with anything?
Hmm.
There are nine million
people in Cairo alone.
I have no idea how many buildings
are out there similar to this one.
There's no way we can find it
by this friggin' picture alone.
Where's Jotaro?
He is in a cafe down the road with Mr.
Joestar.
All right, come on.
Whoa! Ah!
Ah!
Shouldn't you be tamed by now? Jeez!
What? Right. Mm-hmm. Right.
I understand.
I'm afraid the situation has
become most urgent now. Miss Holly?
I was just told that she
lapsed into a coma last night.
Yet we still don't have many
clues as to Dio's whereabouts.
Has the Speedwagon Foundation
been able to find out anything?
Still no information
from them. In addition,
my psychography stopped working just after
I mentally photographed this mansion.
Some kind of psychic
barrier may be in place.
Sir.
Well, just waiting around
here won't solve the problem.
We should do everything we can.
Excuse me.
Ah, excuse me, but we're
looking for this building.
Do you know where this is?
Look, I know you're a visitor,
but I'm trying to run a cafe here.
So could you and your
friends order something?
Oh, right. Sorry about that.
We'll have four iced teas.
Sorry, can't help you.
Let's go.
We'll ask somewhere else.
I'm familiar with that building.
Yes.
Yes, I'm quite certain of it.
You there, did you just
say you know about it?
Yes, sir, I did. You do? Really now?
What great luck! Thank goodness.
Please, tell me, where is it?
Ain't this information
worth something to you?
Ah, right you are.
My apologies, and here's ten pounds.
Now, please, tell me.
You see, sir, I just love to gamble.
I'm a sucker for a cheap thrill, and
I can't seem to stay away from it.
Heck, truth be known, I make my
living on games of luck and skill.
By the way, sir, do you
ever engage in gambling?
I don't understand where
you're going with this.
If you don't care for gambling,
why don't you just say so?
Look here, I'm asking you where
you're going with all this.
What I'm saying is, would you like to bet
against me in a little game of chance?
If you win, I'll tell you
what you want to know.
Free, of course. A bet?
I'm good at winning bets, but we
really have no time for poker games.
Look, I'll pay you 20 pounds more,
so please, tell me where it is.
No, no.
A bag can be made over any little thing.
For example, take a look
at that wall over yonder.
See that cat there?
Now then,
why don't we just bet on which piece of
beef jerky that cat will go after first?
The left one or the right?
Come now, sir.
You have to admit this is exciting.
Listen up and don't be a jerk.
Just take the 30 pounds
and tell us what you know.
Polnareff, you should watch your mouth
when you're asking someone for a favor.
Okay, then.
I'll take your stinking bet.
The cat will go right!
Good.
Now this is getting interesting.
I'll take the one on the left, then.
What's this?
Jotaro, don't you think he is suspicious?
Yeah.
If he makes any strange moves,
attack him. Immediately. I know.
Ah, that cat can smell the jerky now.
Oh, and, uh, by the way, what is
it I have to pay you if I lose?
About a hundred pounds?
No, no money.
Let's play for something more interesting.
Your soul.
Whatever.
Jerking us around, this bastard.
Accept the bet, then?
Your soul it is. Here he comes.
Hold on to your dog now.
Looks like the kitty's going to the right.
If I were that cat, I would
go for the bigger piece.
And the right one looks bigger.
Well, now.
Did you see that it went
for the one on the left
first so I won now what
are you going to do you're
only making it more difficult
to ask for the location
of the building now since
you lost that little game
it's time for you to pay
up huh pay you with what
now sir don't try to welch
on me now I want to soul
you bet you see I'm a stand
user who collects souls
the gambling makes them
that much easier to extract.
I strike when defeat
makes a man vulnerable.
What? Polnareff!
I'm afraid it's too late.
And if I die, Polnareff's
soul goes with me.
So, you best not attack.
Polnareff!
No pulse.
He's dead.
The name is Darby.
Daniel J. Darby.
Oh, and by the way, this here is my cat.
Yeah!
This is Polnareff's soul.
With this, I've eliminated
one of Lord Dio's enemies.
A very foolish one, I might add.
Bastard! How dare you! Bedding?
That cat over there belongs to you.
That is called cheating.
Cheating?
Now, sir, if you can't see through a
simple trick, ain't that your own fault?
Now, to me, gambling is a relationship.
If you think of it as a
relationship of deceit,
then the one who cries first
is the loser, you understand?
Sir, I get the distinct impression you'd
like to kill me with your bare hands.
But what about your friends, so...
Listen, don't think we are just
going to let you get away with this.
September 22nd, 1984,
at exactly 11.15 p .m.
Do y 'all happen to remember
what you were doing right then?
What do you mean?
I remember.
At the time, I was gambling with a man
called Stephen Moore in California.
I mentioned it because he told me
the exact same thing you just said.
That man is now this.
The one below is Moore's father,
and the one next to him is his wife.
As you can see, if you
want Polnareff's soul back,
you have no choice but to continue.
Gamble it with me.
This man is a devil.
This guy's trying to take us one by one!
Well, gents, are you gonna
cash in your chips or what?
Well,
why don't you have a drink and think it
over may I offer you
some chocolate mr.
Joestar what is it
you are doing there.
Right then.
Do you know what surface
tension is Barbie my boy?
Darby sir.
The name is Darby.
It's the molecular attraction
acting on the surface
of that liquor allowing it
to swell without spilling.
Is this a game?
The rules are simple.
We will take turns dropping
coins into this glass and you lose
when the liquor spills over the edge.
Hey old man.
You You cannot do this.
I hereby bet my soul. Good.
No, you cannot do this.
This man is a dirty cheat.
I won't let him cheat.
That's why I chose the nature of the bet.
Jotaro, keep an eye on him.
Very well.
But before we begin, I should like
to inspect those coins in this glass.
You're well within your rights, but
there's something I need to ask.
What's our guarantee that Polnareff's
soul will be returned if you lose?
If I lose, his soul will return.
It's within my stand's
abilities to do that.
My pride as a gambler is all
the guarantee you need, sir.
And what makes you think I'm foolish
enough just to take your word on that?
When engaged in gambling,
people take risks.
They must pay for their actions.
By collecting the souls of others,
I'm risking my own life as well.
That's why I wouldn't lie by my own wager.
Right then.
You go first. Mr. Joestar!
Just trust me.
Well, sir, may I drop in any
number of coins that I wish?
Go ahead, as long as you
drop them all in at once.
Five. Five coins.
Quiet down, and y 'all
please don't touch the table.
Now it's your turn.
You have nerves of steel to
drop in five coins at once.
Well now, I think I'll just play
it safe and stick in one coin.
The old man, he's adding
more liquor to it.
And he tells me to keep an
eye out for any cheating.
What a hustler and a
damn good one at that!
There's no way you can get
any more coins in there.
Well, you're the one that
said that cheating is okay.
Unless you're caught.
Whoa, I was really sweating.
I thought it was going
to spill over for sure?
Well, now it's your turn, Orby, my boy.
Darby!
And I'll thank you not to
make that mistake again, sir.
Darby!
Not Orby or Barbie!
Oh, sorry about that.
Thought he had me for a moment.
Now he's getting the guy bent out of shape
by mispronouncing his name on purpose.
The old man's gotta be
a natural-born gambler.
Well, Darby, shall we
continue with our bet?
It's your turn.
The shadow's blocking my line.
I'd like to drop it in from over here.
Perfectly fine with me.
In any case, the surface
tension has reached its limit.
The merest touch will cause it to spill.
Now I'm sure you must be
thinking, it's impossible.
The surface tension has reached its limit.
But you know what?
You're wrong.
That's impossible!
It has to spill over the edge!
Now, what do you mean
it has to spill over?
Y 'all saw me, didn't you?
I dropped that coin in, so
it's your turn, Mr. Joestar.
He didn't make any funny moves
like he was trying to cheat.
I was watching him with Star Platinum.
He just dropped in all
the coins nice and clean.
I'm sure of it.
It was perfect.
I planned it perfectly so it would
spill over on the very next coin.
Why didn't it? Hurry up, Mr. Joestar.
Y 'all ain't waitin' for that
liquor to dry up, are ya?
I... I...
I can't!
Mr. Joestar!
In his mind, Mr.
Joestar's already admitted his defeat.
That's why his soul was expelled.
Once again, I have won the bet.
That's two chips.
Let's continue gambling.
Unless you're planning to run away
and leave these poor folks behind.
You bastard!
Stop it now, Abdal.
So you still don't get it, do you?
If you kill me, both of
their souls perish as well.
Shit.
Hey, what's going on over here?
If you want to make
trouble, take it outside.
Shut up and mind your own business.
Well done, but too late. Hmm?
Is there something wrong
with that glass, Jotaro?
A piece of melted chocolate
is on the bottom of the glass.
He must have stuck it
on while inspecting the
glass and coins at the
beginning of the game.
I thought we had to understand it.
A cheater is not a cheater
unless he gets caught.
What do you mean?
How can a piece of chocolate allow
more coins to be dropped in the glass?
Although it's melted now,
when he first put the chocolate
on the glass, it was solid,
so it tipped the glass slightly, making
the liquor appear filled to the brim.
When the chocolate melted, it could no
longer support the weight of the glass.
The glass leveled out slowly,
lowering the level of the liquor and
allowing just enough room for one more coin.
What?
But how could he make the chocolate
melt during his turn instead of Mr.
Joestar's?
The heat from the sun.
He protected the glass from direct
sunlight with his own shadow.
Then, when he changed
positions, the chocolate melted.
All right, Darby, get your cards.
We'll settle this once
and for all with poker.
Jotaro!
Well, I consider poker to be my strongest
game, so this should be interesting.
A poker game?
But this guy even beat
Mr. Joestar! I know.
Even though he doesn't use force,
he's the most dangerous stand
user we've ever come across.
But it doesn't matter.
I can't back out of this one.
Before we start, let's try something.
Shuffle those cards.
Huh.
What are you up to, sir?
Pick a card, any card you like.
Just don't let me see it.
Let me take a guess.
Six of hearts.
I'll read the cards in
order, starting from the top.
Five of spades, queen of diamonds,
jack of spades, ace of hearts,
seven of diamonds, six
of clubs, king of clubs.
Huh?
You guessed them all?
But Darby, he shuffled
the cards. How did you...
I can tell you all the cards in order.
Star Platinum's eyes caught everything
you did and saw where every card went.
That's a very interesting parlor trick.
But all it means is
that I have to keep the
cards hidden from view
while I shuffle them,
doesn't it, sir?
Don't you get it?
What I'm telling you is it's not going to
be so easy for you to cheat from now on.
Just a little friendly warning.
Good.
Here's a fresh deck.
Factory sealed.
It includes one Joker.
Looks like a standard deck.
Very well.
Let's start the game.
The Ten of Hearts.
Seven of Clubs.
That makes me the dealer.
Guess I better shuffle
the cards somewhere.
You can't see them, right?
Kindly cut the deck.
What are you doing star
platinum just broke
darby's finger why did
you do that i warned you!
I'm not going to overlook
any cheating from
now on cheating when i
did not see him make any?
Suspicious moves look
carefully at those cards
he's got in his hand the
second card from the top!
That's hanging is the card he tried
to deal to me just now he pretended to
deal the cards in order From the top
but actually intended to deal me the
second card so the card on top would
have gone to Him giving him a winning
hand of three of a kind you're brutal
man you broke my finger on the contrary.
Mary, I'm full of mercy.
I could have severed your finger.
Good.
Cheating takes advantage of
psychological blind spots.
Having good vision ain't
enough to catch cheating.
I didn't expect you to
see me deal in seconds.
I'll take this lesson to heart and
won't underestimate anyone again.
This finger will be accepted
as a reminder of that.
But, Jotaro, I'm not here to
fight for Lord Dio. No, sir.
I came here to fight because
I'm a born gambling man.
and I'm going to challenge you
with all my strength and soul.
I've split each one of
their souls into six chips.
Poker is the type of gambling
game that allows you to
quit when you know you'll
lose it against your opponent.
But because you have to pay for each turn,
two chips are not enough to play a game.
Three is the minimum.
A soul is returned only after you
win all six chips back, understood?
Jotaro,
I'd like to offer you
some chips if y 'all still
willing to engage in
this here gambling game,
but I need to hear y 'all
say those little words.
All right, I will bet my soul.
Good.
Jotaro! Well,
since you can't shuffle
with that hand of yours,
why don't we get a third
party to do it for us?
Abdul, let's ask that kid
on the hill over there.
Bring him here. Okay.
This here stack of Snow White chips.
They represent your immortal soul, sir.
When I take all six of them, I will
add your soul to my collection.
Sorry, we need you to
do this for us. Okay.
As for the ante, one little Polnareff.
Let's begin.
Well, let's see now.
I'll take two cards.
Give me three.
My, my.
Just look at you.
Seems you got a good hand, huh?
Let's see how it goes?
I'll raise one Polnareff
for the time being!
Same here!
Unless he folds?
At least three chips are needed per hand.
Well, I call.
Show me your hand.
Two pair, eights and nines. Sorry, bud.
Two pair, queens or jacks?
Goodness on me.
I almost went and lost this here game.
Three chips left.
Let's go on to the next hand.
Deal the cards.
Yes, another game.
I sure hope it won't
be your last game, sir.
I'll take one.
What's wrong, sir?
Hurry up and look at your cards, so you
can decide if you're going to draw a fold.
I've decided that I'm going to hold.
Eh?
Uh, could you kindly repeat that, sir?
I'm sure I must have heard you wrong.
You're saying you're keeping them?
That's what I said.
I'm keeping them.
I'm going to bet with
these five cards. I know!
I know you just want to
hold on to your cards.
But why didn't you look at them first?
I'll keep them.
Answer my question, sir.
How can you play the game
without looking at your cards?
Hey, kid, don't worry about this.
Just stay calm and deal
the cards, all right?
All right.
Hey, Avdol, I need a favor. A favor?
I'll go along with that.
But why aren't you looking at your cards?
How dare you ignore me like that?
I demand that you answer me!
In addition to my remaining chips,
I'm going to raise you all
of Avdol's soul. Huh? What?
Darby, you are a very cool-headed man.
You take careful, calculated actions.
You do not use force, yet
you are a very powerful man.
My personality is not suited for gambling.
I'm the type to lose my temper too easily.
If I play against you, I
will most certainly lose.
But I believe in Jotaro.
I do not yet understand his reasons
for leaving those cards face down.
But if Jotaro wants me to
bet, I will trust him and bet.
My soul, or whatever else it may take!
Well now,
it appears you gentlemen
are taking leave of
your senses from the
pressure of this game.
Hey!
I asked you for a card, boy!
Now hurry up! Uh, okay.
Mr.
Darby, I did as you asked.
I dealt him a bum hand.
This man is nothing.
There's no mistake. I'm certain.
Jotaro may think he chose
some innocent child, but I,
Darby, owned this here shop and
everyone within a stone's throw of it.
No matter who he chooses to deal,
the results will be the same.
His cards will be nothing but garbage.
Betting without looking at
his cards, he's bluffing.
How dare you bluff against me?
What makes you think I'm
gonna fold, you fool?
All right.
I'll see you two chips, sir,
and hear all six Polnareffs.
And, for laughs,
I'm raising your six Josephs!
That's fifteen chips in
all! What? Wait a minute.
Jotaro has no more chips
left to call your bet.
No more chips?
He still has some. What do you mean?
Well, now, all he needs to do is write
me out a little old promisorite note.
That's just as good as gold as
far as my stand is concerned.
Like I said, what are you talking about?
Why he can bet the soul of his friend
Kakyoin, who's hospitalized in Aswa.
What?
Come on boys, start sweating.
How dare you try to bluff me, Darby.
I'll turn that poker face of
yours into a mask of fear.
Then it's agreed.
I'll raise you all of Kakyoin's soul.
Jotaro, that soul belongs
to someone who's not here.
Am I being selfish?
Hey Jotaro, what you trying to pull?
What are you talking about?
What did I do?
That smoke there?
What's the matter?
Are you feeling sick?
Where did that cigarette
come from just now?
I thought I saw Star Platinum light it up.
What confidence could it be?
Did Star Platinum switch those
cards without me noticing?
No, I was watching his cards carefully.
I didn't see the cigarette only
because I was concentrating.
On his cards
four
of a
kind with kings to have
a better hand than this
he'd need four of a
kind with aces, a straight flush,
or five of a kind with the joker.
Jotaro's cards are rags.
For him to make a good hand, he would
have needed to switch all five cards.
No matter how vast Star Platinum may be,
is it really possible that he could have
switched not one, but all five cards
without attracting my
attention in the slightest?
It can't be.
It's impossible.
There is absolutely no way
he could have switched all
five cards without a veteran
gambler like me noticing
in something.
Alrighty then, Jotaro.
You want a showdown?
I'll give you one.
Try to pull a useless bluff on
me with that stupid cigarette.
Huh?
You got yourself a treat now?
When did you...
How dare you?
Alright, showdown. Hold on.
I'm not finished.
There's the little matter
of a raise I'd like to make.
What the?
You're raising?
But you're out of chips.
I'm gonna
raise you.
I'm gonna raise you my mother's soul.
What?
Your mother's?
Jotaro, not Miss Holly's soul.
I came here to Egypt for one
reason, to save my mother.
So she would have no objections
whatsoever for me to bet
the six chips of her soul.
But Darby,
I'm going to ask you to see Be my bet with
something that's equal in
value to my mother-soul.
If you lose, you have to reveal
the secret of Dio's stand.
That reaction? He knows.
He knows Dio's secret.
But if Darby talks, he'll lose his life.
A traitor would be killed!
Your confidence must mean
you have a winning hand.
Is it really all right to assume that?
Those cards will surely
win, right, Chotaro?
Come on, are you going to call or fold?
Say it out loud right now!
Darby!
Honestly, I'm the greatest
I've got to accept you, guys.
I'm going to...
That...
that man just...
What's wrong with him?
He passed out.
The two souls! They're saved!
He must have passed out
from too much tension.
He conceded the game.
In his mind, he'd folded the cards.
So all the souls he captured are now
released since he has admitted his defeat.
Four of a kind!
In his hand, he had four kings!
Jotaro, those face-down cards
of yours, what were they?
Oh, I thought so!
Nothing but garbage!
No matter how quick Star Platinum is,
there's no way I could have
cheated around a man like Darby.
My plan was to get him
to be scared and fold.
I would have freaked out if I'd
known I had this crappy hand.
Freaked out?
Jotaro, I can't believe you took
such a chance on those lousy cards.
By the way, kid, you
just said I thought so.
Does that mean you knew
what my cards were?
Hey, everyone!
Let's play Macho.
That coming is a lot of fun.
Dice is thrilling too.
No matter what, I'm always the best.
Hey, now tell us, where's that mansion?
Old Cairo, where the
whorehouse used to be.
Dio, stand.
What is its secret?
No. No!
The way he is now.
I do not think we will ever
get Dio's secret out of him.
He was definitely formidable.
He tried to defeat all
four of us by himself.
That's pretty impressive.
At any rate, I'd say we're lucky to have
found out the location of the mansion.
We don't have any more time to waste.
VINCIROR
VINCERO VINCERO
VINCERO
I love you, I love
you?
Thank you.